Hello English learners and welcome to another lesson with EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎来到EnglishPod的另一节课。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you a great Christmas lesson.
今天我们为大家带来一堂精彩的圣诞课。
That's right.
没错。
We've got a lot of Christmas vocabulary in today's lesson for you.
今天的课程中我们准备了很多圣诞词汇。
Yeah, it's almost Christmas time so everyone is getting into the spirit, especially here
是啊，快到圣诞节了，大家都沉浸在节日气氛中，尤其是在EnglishPod这里，
at EnglishPod, so we're going to teach you a little bit more about this.
所以我们来教大家更多这方面的内容。
Speaking of the spirit, I think it's time for us to look at our vocabulary preview.
说到节日气氛，我想是时候看看我们的词汇预览了。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
So in this part of our show, we'll look at some key language in the dialogue that you'll
在这一部分，我们会看一些对话中的关键语言，
need to know to understand the dialogue.
你需要了解这些才能理解对话。
And actually today we only have one word.
实际上今天只有一个词。
Eggnog.
蛋奶酒。
E-G-G-N-O-G.
E-G-G-N-O-G。
Eggnog.
蛋奶酒。
So, eggnog is a really popular Christmas drink.
蛋奶酒是一种非常流行的圣诞饮品。
It's a traditional Christmas drink.
它是一种传统的圣诞饮品。
Right.
对。
What is it made of?
它是由什么做的？
It's eggs, cream, sugar, and usually rum.
鸡蛋、奶油、糖，通常还有朗姆酒。
Rum.
朗姆酒。
Oh, so it has alcohol.
哦，所以它含酒精。
Yeah, normally it has alcohol.
是的，通常含酒精。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
好吧。
That's interesting.
真有意思。
There's actually a drink very similar to this in Chile.
实际上在智利有一种非常类似的饮品。
Really?
真的吗？
Yep.
是的。
They call it monkey tail.
他们叫它猴尾酒。
So in Spanish that would be...
用西班牙语说就是……
Cola de mono.
Cola de mono。
Very nice.
很不错。
Yeah, so it's actually really, really good.
是的，它真的非常好喝。
I mean, it's really similar to eggnog.
我是说，它和蛋奶酒真的很像。
Okay.
好的。
So with that in mind, let's take a listen to our dialogue for the first time.
那么带着这些，让我们第一次来听一下对话。
I hate working on Christmas Eve.
我讨厌在圣诞前夜工作。
Whoa, get a load of this guy.
哇，看看这家伙。
Come in, Central.
呼叫总部。
I think we got ourselves a situation here.
我想我们这儿有情况了。
License and registration, please.
请出示驾照和登记证。
Have you been drinking tonight, sir?
先生，您今晚喝酒了吗？
I had one or two glasses of eggnog, but nothing else.
我只喝了一两杯蛋奶酒，别的没喝。
Step out of the vehicle, please.
请下车。
Sir, what do you have in the back?
先生，您后面装的是什么？
Just a few Christmas gifts.
只是一些圣诞礼物。
Tis the season, after all.
毕竟这是圣诞季。
Don't take that tone with me.
别用那种语气跟我说话。
Do you have an invoice for these items?
这些物品有发票吗？
Oh, no.
哦，不。
I make these in my workshop in the North Pole.
这些是我在北极的工坊里做的。
You are under arrest, sir.
先生，您被捕了。
You have the right to remain silent.
你有权保持沉默。
You better not pout.
你最好别撅嘴。
You better not cry.
你最好别哭。
Anything you say can and will be used against you.
你所说的一切都可能被用作对你不利的证据。
You have the right to an attorney.
你有权请律师。
If you can't afford one, the state will appoint one for you.
如果你请不起，州政府会为你指派一位。
Do you understand these rights that have just been read to you?
你明白刚才向你宣读的这些权利了吗？
You can't take me to jail.
你不能带我去监狱。
What about my sleigh?
我的雪橇怎么办？
It's Christmas Eve.
今天是圣诞前夜。
I have presents to deliver.
我还有礼物要送。
Rudolph, prancer, dancer, good health!
鲁道夫、猛冲、舞者，祝你们健康！
Well I did not see that one coming.
我真没想到会这样。
That was interesting.
真有意思。
Santa Claus is being taken to jail.
圣诞老人要被送进监狱了。
What's gonna happen next, Marco?
接下来会发生什么，马可？
I don't know.
我不知道。
We'll talk about that in a little while.
我们一会儿再讨论这个。
Let's take a look at some language from this dialogue.
我们来看看这段对话中的一些语言点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
So the first word that we have on our language takeaway today is vehicle.
今天语言要点的第一个词是 vehicle。
Vehicle.
Vehicle。
So this is a vehicle.
所以这是一个交通工具。
And this is a vehicle.
这也是一个交通工具。
这还是一个交通工具。
So all of those are vehicles.
所以所有这些都是交通工具。
Now I thought that a vehicle was a car specifically.
我之前以为交通工具特指汽车。
No, any machine that carries people from one place to another is a vehicle.
不，任何把人从一个地方运到另一个地方的机器都是交通工具。
Great.
太好了。
Alright.
好的。
Let's take a look now at our second word.
现在我们来看第二个词。
Attorney.
律师。
So what is an attorney?
那么什么是律师？
A lawyer.
律师。
Well that's simple enough.
这很简单。
Yep, a lawyer.
是的，律师。
Let's move to our third word which is appoint.
我们来看第三个词，任命。
Appoint.
任命。
So appoint means choose.
所以任命的意思是选择。
Okay, so the president of a country might appoint his chief of staff.
好的，所以一个国家的总统可能会任命他的幕僚长。
Right, or I can appoint my attorney.
对，或者我可以任命我的律师。
True.
没错。
So can you appoint a thing?
那么你能任命一个东西吗？
Can I appoint my coffee cup?
我能任命我的咖啡杯吗？
No, no.
不，不行。
You only use it for people.
这个词只用于人。
You choose someone.
你选择某人。
Okay, appoint.
好的，任命。
You can't choose something.
你不能选择某个东西。
So I appoint someone.
所以我任命某人。
Exactly.
正是。
Alright, let's move to our final word.
好了，我们来看最后一个词。
Sleigh.
雪橇。
So, Erica, you're from Canada.
那么，埃里卡，你来自加拿大。
You can tell us about sleighs.
你可以给我们讲讲雪橇。
Alright.
好的。
A sleigh is a vehicle that is pulled by a horse and travels over snow or ice.
雪橇是一种由马拉着在雪地或冰面上行驶的交通工具。
Okay.
嗯。
So, you know, like Santa drives a sleigh.
所以，你知道，就像圣诞老人驾驶雪橇一样。
He drives a sleigh.
他驾驶雪橇。
So do you drive a sleigh or ride a sleigh?
那么你是驾驶雪橇还是乘坐雪橇？
Good question.
好问题。
Well, the song says you ride in a one-horse open sleigh.
嗯，歌词里说“你乘坐一匹马拉的开放式雪橇”。
Right, okay.
对，没错。
Well, you know what?
嗯，你知道吗？
I think it's time for us to look at some interesting phrases that we found in this dialogue.
我想是时候看看我们在对话中发现的一些有趣短语了。
So let's look at putting it together.
那我们来看看“整合”部分。
Putting it together.
整合。
Today on Putting it Together, we have two great phrases for you and let's take a look
今天的“整合”环节，我们为你准备了两个很棒的短语，先来看看
at the first one.
第一个。
Step out.
出来。
So step out means to go out of a place for a short period of time.
所以“step out”的意思是短暂地离开某个地方。
Right.
对。
So in our dialogue, for example, the police officer said, step out of the vehicle.
比如在我们的对话中，警察说“从车里出来”。
Get out of your vehicle.
从你的车里出来。
You can also say, step out of the office.
你也可以说“走出办公室”。
You can say, I just stepped out of the shower.
你可以说“我刚洗完澡出来”。
Right.
对。
Now, we can also say, step in.
我们也可以说“进来”。
It's the opposite.
这是反义词。
The opposite, right?
反义词，对吧？
I can ask Marco, step into my office for a moment.
我可以对马可说，“请到我办公室来一下”。
Oh, okay.
哦，好的。
So that's step out and step in.
这就是“step out”和“step in”。
Great phrases.
很棒的短语。
Let's take a look at our final phrase.
我们来看看最后一个短语。
Get a load of.
瞧瞧。
So when I say get a load of something, I mean look at, right?
所以当我说“get a load of something”时，我的意思是“看”，对吧？
Right.
对。
Look at this guy.
看看这家伙。
Get a load of this guy.
瞧瞧这家伙。
Yeah, that's what we heard in the dialogue.
是的，这就是我们在对话中听到的。
Now, you can use this phrase in a number of different ways and we have some examples for
现在，你可以用多种不同的方式使用这个短语，我们有一些例子给
you.
你。
Example one.
例子一。
Get a load of this.
你瞧瞧这个。
A war has started in Antarctica.
南极洲爆发了一场战争。
Example two.
例子二。
Get a load of that house.
你瞧瞧那栋房子。
It's so big.
它真大。
Example three.
例子三。
Get a load of him.
你瞧瞧他。
He's wearing a pink suit.
他穿着一身粉色西装。
Okay, I think we've covered a lot of interesting words and phrases, so we are ready to listen
好了，我想我们已经涵盖了很多有趣的单词和短语，所以我们准备好再听一遍
to our dialogue a second time.
我们的对话。
But this time it's going to be a little bit slower so we can pick up all these great words.
但这次会慢一点，这样我们就能听懂所有这些好词了。
I hate working on Christmas Eve.
我讨厌在平安夜工作。
Whoa, get a load of this guy.
哇，你瞧瞧这家伙。
Come in central.
呼叫总部。
I think we got ourselves a situation here.
我想我们这里遇到情况了。
Passes and registration please.
请出示通行证和登记证。
Have you been drinking tonight, sir?
先生，您今晚喝酒了吗？
I had one or two glasses of eggnog, but nothing else.
我喝了一两杯蛋奶酒，但没别的了。
Step out of the vehicle, please.
请下车。
Sir, what do you have in the back?
先生，你后面有什么？
Just a few Christmas gifts.
只是一些圣诞礼物。
Tis the season, after all.
毕竟这是节日季节。
Don't take that tone with me.
别用那种语气跟我说话。
Do you have an invoice for these items?
这些物品你有发票吗？
Um, no.
嗯，没有。
I make these in my workshop in the North Pole.
这些是我在北极的工作室里做的。
You are under arrest, sir.
你被捕了，先生。
You have the right to remain silent.
你有权保持沉默。
You better not pout.
你最好别撅嘴。
You better not cry.
你最好别哭。
Anything you say can and will be used against you.
你所说的一切都可能被用作对你不利的证据。
You have the right to an attorney.
你有权请律师。
If you cannot afford one, the state will appoint one for you.
如果你请不起，州政府会为你指定一位。
Do you understand all these rights that have just been read to you?
你明白刚才向你宣读的这些权利了吗？
You can't take me to jail.
你不能带我去监狱。
What about my sleigh?
我的雪橇怎么办？
It's Christmas Eve.
今天是平安夜。
I have presents to deliver.
我有礼物要送。
Rudolph, prancer, dancer, get help.
鲁道夫、猛冲者、舞者，快来帮忙。
Okay, so we noticed some really great words and phrases and with this, now we can start
好的，我们注意到了一些很棒的单词和短语，现在我们可以开始
with some Fluency Builder.
流利度训练了。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Today, on Fluency Builder, we have two great phrases that you can use to sound a little
今天，在流利度训练中，我们有两个很棒的短语，你可以用它们让你的口语听起来更
bit more natural when you speak.
自然一些。
That's right.
没错。
Our first phrase you can use if you want to say, don't speak to me like that.
第一个短语，如果你想表达“别那样跟我说话”，可以用它。
Don't take that tone with me.
别用那种语气跟我说话。
So you often hear this phrase coming out of the mouth of a mother or a father.
你经常听到这个短语从妈妈或爸爸嘴里说出来。
Yeah, when their children are maybe talking back.
是的，当他们的孩子顶嘴的时候。
Yeah.
嗯。
Don't take that tone with me, young man.
别用那种语气跟我说话，年轻人。
I used to get that a lot.
我以前经常听到这句话。
Really?
真的吗？
I'm not sure about that.
我不太确定。
Okay, our second phrase, we use it when we have a problem.
好的，第二个短语，当我们遇到问题时使用。
The phrase we heard in the dialogue was, I think we've got ourselves a situation here.
我们在对话中听到的短语是：我想我们这里遇到情况了。
Let's listen to another example.
让我们再听一个例子。
Houston, we've got ourselves a situation here.
休斯顿，我们这里遇到情况了。
Sometimes I use this phrase when I want to tell my boss that I have a problem.
有时我想告诉老板我遇到问题时，会用这个短语。
I might say, boss, I've got a bit of a situation.
我可能会说：老板，我有点情况。
Can you help me with it?
你能帮我处理一下吗？
Okay.
好的。
Yeah, I have a little bit of a problem.
是的，我有点小问题。
Yeah.
嗯。
Useful phrases, hey?
有用的短语，对吧？
Really useful phrases.
非常有用的短语。
Great stuff.
太棒了。
So now we can listen to our dialogue a final time and this time we can understand everything
现在我们可以最后听一遍对话，这次我们能理解里面的
that's in it.
所有内容了。
I hate working on Christmas Eve.
我讨厌在平安夜工作。
Whoa, get a load of this guy.
哇，看看这家伙。
Come in, Central.
进来，中央控制室。
I think we've got ourselves a situation here.
我想我们这里遇到情况了。
License and registration, please.
请出示驾照和登记证。
Have you been drinking tonight, sir?
先生，您今晚喝酒了吗？
I had one or two glasses of eggnog, but nothing else.
我只喝了一两杯蛋奶酒，别的没喝。
Step out of the vehicle, please.
请下车。
Sir, what do you have in the back?
先生，您后面装的是什么？
Just a few Christmas gifts.
只是一些圣诞礼物。
Tis the season, after all.
毕竟现在是节日季。
Don't take that tone with me.
别用那种语气跟我说话。
Do you have an invoice for these items?
这些物品有发票吗？
Oh, no.
哦，没有。
I make these in my workshop in the North Pole.
这些是我在北极的工坊里做的。
You are under arrest, sir.
先生，您被捕了。
You have the right to remain silent.
你有权保持沉默。
You better not pout.
你最好别撅嘴。
You better not cry.
你最好别哭。
Anything you say can and will be used against you.
你所说的一切都可能被用作对你不利的证据。
You have the right to an attorney.
你有权请律师。
If you can't afford one, the state will appoint one for you.
如果你请不起，州政府会为你指派一位。
Do you understand these rights that have just been read to you?
你明白刚才向你宣读的这些权利了吗？
You can't take me to jail.
你不能把我关进监狱。
What about my sleigh?
我的雪橇怎么办？
It's Christmas Eve.
今天是圣诞前夜。
I have presents to deliver.
我还有礼物要送。
Rudolph, prancer, dancer, good health.
鲁道夫、猛冲、舞者，祝你们健康。
So when the police officer was arresting Santa Claus, he said something a little bit strange,
所以当警察逮捕圣诞老人时，他说了一些有点奇怪的话，
hey?
是吧？
Yeah, he said, you better not pout.
是啊，他说：你最好别撅嘴。
You better not cry.
你最好别哭。
Now, are those part of the normal rights that a police officer reads?
这些是警察通常宣读的权利的一部分吗？
No, no.
不，不是。
They're not part of the normal rights.
它们不是常规权利的一部分。
It's actually from a Christmas song, so let's listen to how it goes in the song.
这实际上来自一首圣诞歌，我们来听听歌里是怎么唱的。
You better watch out.
你最好当心。
You better not cry.
你最好别哭。
You better not pout.
你最好别撅嘴。
I'm telling you why.
我来告诉你为什么。
Santa Claus is coming to town.
圣诞老人要进城了。
I'm pretty happy we had a song to play there instead of us having to sing.
我很高兴我们有首歌可以放，不用自己唱。
Yeah, but that's great because if the children cry or if they are not good kids, then Santa
是啊，但这很好，因为如果孩子们哭或者不是好孩子，圣诞老人就不会给他们礼物。
Claus will not give them presents.
所以这就是原因。
So that's why.
Okay, listeners, I hope that you're not pouting.
好了，听众们，希望你们没有在撅嘴。
I hope you're not crying, but it's time for us to go.
希望你们没有在哭，但我们该走了。
So be sure to go to our website at EnglishPod.com and be sure to leave all your questions and
所以一定要访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，留下你们的所有问题、
comments and maybe some of your Christmas stories.
评论，也许还有你们的圣诞故事。
All right, thanks for listening and until next time, goodbye.
好了，感谢收听，下次再见，拜拜。